好了  各位  今晚最后一把
All right, everybody, last hand for the night.
不是吧  现在才
Aw... Phooey. It's only... Ah!
还不到午夜
It's not even midnight.
人家早上还要工作
Some people have jobs to go to in the morning.
我儿子  就一工作狂
Oh, my son, the working stiff.
不跟
Phooey. I fold.
理查德女士  抱歉您很多次没跟了
If you don't mind me saying, Mrs. R., you fold a lot.
我只是不相信手气会转好
I just don't believe in stringing along a bad hand.
何必浪费时间
Why waste time?
事实上  我妈在行的不是德州扑克
Actually, mother's game isn't really texas hold'em.
而是脱衣扑克
It's strip poker.
能让乐子一刻不停  如果你明白我的意思
Keeps things humming along, if you know what I mean.
坦白讲我更喜欢脱衣扑克
Well, frankly, I prefer strip,
因为即便你输了也是赢家
because even when you lose, you win.
-加注20  -跟
- Raise $20. - Call.
加到100
Make it a hundred..
-100美元  -拿出男人的气魄伙计
- 100 bucks? - Man up, bro.
不是吧
Really?
-不跟了  -放弃
- I'm out. - Slop.
卡塞尔你呢  你已经为很久没跟了
What about you, castle? You're already in for the blind.
敢不敢玩点"刺激"的
Not scared of a little...action, are you?
"刺激"是我的中间名
"Action" is my middle name.
别担心  亲爱的  他在虚张声势
Don't worry, sweetheart, he's bluffing
每当他眼睛眨个不停的时候
Whenever he blinks too much,
就说明他的牌很臭
It means he's got a lousy hand.
妈
Mother.
-我打住  -好了继续发牌
- Well... - All right, here we go.
好了
There it is.
-糟了  -怎么了
- Uh-Oh. - What?
他不眨眼了转而敲牌
He's not blinking, but now he's tapping,
说明他可能来了张好牌
Which means he might have the nuts..
那又如何
What's the matter?
你不会害怕玩点刺激的  对吧
You're not afraid of a little action, are you?
全部押上
All in.
-了结他  贝克特  -让他大出血
- Take him down, beckett. - Yeah, make him pay.
这次写书的能耐帮不上了  卡塞尔
Can't write your way out of this one, huh, castle?
干得好  贝克特
Way to go, beckett.
或许有人该把中间名换做"衰人"了
Maybe someone should change their middle name to "loser"
"衰人"
Loser.
无话可说  今晚不走运
What can I say. Guess it just wasn't my night.
看见没  我说他眨眼  那是
Ah, see, I told you he was bluffing. It's the...
那眨眼睛的理论  没错你说得对
It's the blinking thing, yeah, you're right.
我们20分钟内到
Yeah, we'll be there in 20.
亨利大街发生凶杀案
Homicide on henry street.
-我帮你处理这些  -谢谢
- I'll take care of this for you. - Thank you.
至少你们已经在市中心了
Well, at least you guys are already downtown.
但是已经过了午夜
But it's after midnight.
谋杀从不停歇  理查德夫人
Murder never sleeps, Mrs. R.
我们也是
Yeah, neither do we.
有人说"谋杀"
Oh. Oh. Someone say "murder"?
等我一下  我拿上外套
Hold on, I'll get my coat..
看他兴奋的
Look at him, all excited..
像个过圣诞节的孩子一样
Yeah, like a kid at christmas..
圣诞树下躺着一具尸体
With a dead body under the tree.
-是机油吗  -看上去挺像
- It's motor oil, all right. - Looks like it,
不过我要从浴缸抽点样本  化验后才能确认
But I'll have to pump out the tub and run some tests to be sure.
的确是机油  10W-40型号的
It's motor oil, all right. 10W-40.
衣橱里有装机油的空瓶
Empties in the closet.
什么样的变态  会把一个女人溺死在机油里
What kind of a freak drowns a woman in motor oil?
有人试图说明点什么
Someone's trying to send a message.
我已经和军装警察说过了
I already told the uniforms.
客人登记入住之后
Once people check in,
我可不管他们在里头做什么
I don't wanna know what they do up there.
她的钱包不见了  又没有身份证
Her purse was missing, and she didn't have an I.D. on her.
是否有可能用信用卡付房费
Any chance she paid for the room with a credit card?
我只能告诉你一点  死者是周五租的房
All I can tell you is, whoever rented the room on friday
用现金付了五天的房租
Paid cash for a 5-day stay
他们本应于今晚离开
They were supposed to be out tonight.
因此到了午夜  我上去查房
So at midnight, I went up to check
看看房间是否空出来了
If the place was empty
没想到见她死在浴缸里
and found her in the tub.
打扫起来麻烦得很
It's gonna be a bitch to clean it.
那么如果有人来这边找她
So if anybody was meeting her here...
这里可不是来客人  会有电话通知的
It's not like the guests arrive and I ring them up!
-这可不是豪华旅馆  -明白了
- This ain't the ritz. - Clearly.
今晚呢  有没有举止怪异的人进出
What about tonight? Anyone strange coming in or going out?
比尔
Hey, bill.
茉莉  玩的开心吗
Jasmine, how's it hangin'?
我想半数的客人都符合你说的特征
I think you just described half their clientele.
女性  身份不明
Unidentified woman--
四十岁出头  健康状况良好
Early 40s, good health.
她带着结婚戒指  但上面没有刻字
She's wearing a wedding ring, but there's no inscription.
-死因  -溺毙
- Cause of death? - Drowning.
她的头部后面有严重挫伤
And there's a nasty contusion on the back of her head.
也就是说  有人把她打晕了
So somebody hit her hard enough to knock her out
然后给她来了一个机油浴
And then gave her a motor oil bath.
我在她的一个口袋找到这个
And I found this in one of her pockets.
北方铁路的票根
Ticket stub for the metro-North.
受害人是昨天早上
Our victim took the train in
从威彻斯特坐火车过来的
from westchester yesterday morning.
从威彻斯特到曼哈顿南部
Westchester to lower manhattan?
大老远赶来就为了次机油浴
That's a long way to go for a lube job.
已婚女人入住廉价旅馆
See, when married ladies go to cheap hotels,
十有八九是因为性
It's always about sex.
或者毒品
Or drugs.
从一个酒杯的取样中
The sample in one of the wine glasses
-检测到了雷米安的成分  -一种安眠药
- Tested positive for remian. - A sleeping pill.
-对  -这不是冲动性谋杀
- Mm-mm.  - This was not a crime of passion.
有人租了五天的房
That room was rented for five days
还在里头藏了机油
And someone stocked the place up with motor oil.
这是精心设计的
That takes planning.
漂亮的郊区女性
And nice suburban ladies
乘火车进城却没有回家
don't just take the train into the city
不可能没人发觉
And not return without somebody noticing.
欧文顿警局昨晚接到一个名叫
Irvington P.D. Logged a call last night
迈克尔·高德曼的人的报案电话
from a Michael Goldman wanting to report
他的妻子艾莉森失踪
His wife Allison missing.
衣服和外貌与死者相符
Clothing and description match.
说她进城工作却没有回家
Said she went into the city for work and never came back.
他说感到情况不对
Said he knew that something was wrong.
可怜的家伙  除非他就是凶手
Poor guy. Unless he's the killer...
试图在尸体发现前
And he's covering his tracks by calling the police
通过报案掩饰罪行
Before the body's discovered.
在拘捕他之前先问问情况怎么样
How about we question him before we convict him?
有地址吗
You got an address?
谢谢
Thanks.
我不明白
I don't un-understand.
你说在哪里发现她尸体的
Where did you say that she was found?
市区的一个廉价旅馆
At an S.R.O. in the city..
就是一个单人间  类似供短期逗留的旅馆
It's a single room occupancy. It's like a transient hotel.
她怎么会呆在那里
Why would she be in a place like that?
你知道她在那里要和谁见面吗
Can you think of anyone she might've been meeting?
不知道
No.
探长  我们的婚姻很幸福
My wife and I were happily married, detective.
我们坦诚相待
We had no secrets.
你昨晚告诉警察你妻子
You told police last night that your wife went into the city
-因工作而进城  -她做兼职
- For her job? - She was working part-time..
这几年我们财政状况不好
We'd had some financial setbacks the last few years.
我暂时失业  我们不得不卖掉公寓
I'd been laid off, and we had to give up the apartment.
你妻子对于搬到郊区怎么看的
How did your wife handle the move to the suburbs?
不太能接受
Not, uh, not too well.
艾莉森想念城市生活  因此几个月前
Allison missed the city, so a couple months ago,
她在曼哈顿的一家服装店
She got a job working three days a week
找到了一份一周三天的工作
At a clothing boutique in Manhattan...
就在72大街  里涵服装店
This little place on 72nd called Lehane's.
她说在那里工作
She said that being there...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
她说在那里工作
She said that being there...
勾起她很多对过去美好时光的回忆
Reminded her of the good old days.
我试图把艾莉森·高德曼死前
So I'm trying to put together a timeline
几小时的行程整理出来
Of Allison Goldman's last hours.
首先我打电话给里涵服装店
First call I make is to Lehane's,
就是艾莉森工作的地方
the store where she worked.
我对店主说  早上好
I say to the owner, "good morning, sir
我想和你谈谈你的员工
I'd like to talk to you about your employee
-艾莉森·高德曼  -他说什么
- Allison Goldman. - And?
他说是谁
And he says, "who?".
艾莉森不在那里工作
Allison didn't work there.
昨天没有以前也没有
Not yesterday, not ever..
如果她一周进城三次
Well, if she wasn't going into the city
不是为了工作
Three times a week for a job
那她进城做什么
Then what was she doing there?
而且每个周五晚上又从哪里搞到的
And how did she come home friday night
四百美元贴补家用
With 400 bucks in cash for the family kitty?
或许卡塞尔是对的  和性有关
Maybe Castle was right. Maybe this was about sex.
她可是个好母亲
The lady was a soccer mom.
三点半路过我女儿的学校
Come by my daughter's school about 3:30.
那地方简直是天堂
The place is like happy hour..
或者她有个男朋友
Maybe she had a boyfriend..
在萨巴斯商店[专卖高级食品的超市]
Yes, a boyfriend...
排队认识了一位男朋友
Someone she met in line at Zabar
或者是一个下午在博物馆
Or, uh, one afternoon at the museum
她为躲雨  进入了博物馆
When she, uh, ducked in to escape a rainstorm.
也可能是她之前就在市区认识的人
Maybe it was someone she already knew from the city,
一个让她想起美好时光的人
Someone who reminded her of when times were good,
在被迫离开有水景的
Before she had to give up  that cute apartment
可爱公寓之前的时光
With the partial river view.
也许有人给她点小钱花
Someone who was slipping her a little cash
作为报偿她向其提供一些服务
While he was slipping her something else.
艾莉森·高德曼不像随便和人好上的人
Yeah, Allison Goldman wouldn't have some cheap affair.
这个人对可能对她有重大意义
This person would've had to have meant something to her...
一个关心她  倾听她的人
Someone who cared for her, someone who listened to her.
而现在他希望自己的付出要有回报
Only now he wanted a little more return for his investment,
做一些她不愿意做的事
Something she wasn't willing to do.
例如离开她丈夫
Like leave her husband.
她不同意  于是他动粗
And when she wouldn't, then he got violent..
没错
Yep.
这太荒谬了  我现在正寻找线索
You know, I feel so stupid. Here I am looking for evidence,
而你们却靠编故事了事
And all I had to do was just make something up
那么这个假想的男友杀手
So this imaginary boyfriend killer..
你们假想出他的地址没
Do you think that he has an imaginary address?
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett?
高德曼先生  什么事
Mr. Goldman, what is it?
我的律师今早给社保办公室打电话
My lawyer called the social security office this morning
好让他们知道艾莉森去世了
To let them know that Allison had passed away.
两小时前他传真了这个给我
He faxed this to me two hours ago.
死亡证明
A death certificate?
艾莉森·波特的死亡证明
Yeah. For Allison Porter.
波特是我妻子娘家的姓
Now Porter was my wife's maiden name.
不过上面说
But it says here
艾莉森·波特早在1963年就去世了
that Allison Porter died in 1963.
这个波特死的时候才三个月
When she was 3 months old.
但这个已故孩子的社保号码
But this child's social security number
和我妻子的一模一样
Is the same as my wife's.
我妻子不是她自己说的那个人
My wife wasn't the womanshe said she was.
我们在一起的日子
Our whole life together...
是一个弥天大谎
Was a lie.
二十年了
So for 20 years,
这个女人都用一个假名生活
This woman was living under a false name?
-这太疯狂了  -她丈夫无比震惊
- That's crazy.. - Yeah, her husband was pretty shaken up.
儿子这次信我  当一个女人嫁给男人
Trust me on this one, kiddo. When a woman marries a man
却20年不告诉他自己的身份
And doesn't bother to tell him who she is for 20 years,
说明她是个罪犯
She's a crimina...
玛塔·哈莉[一战间谍舞蹈家]  影夫人都是如此
Mata Hari, shady lady.
换句话说  她是个好演员
In other words, a very good actress..
说到这里  你似乎遗传了
Speaking of which... You seem to have inherited
-我的部分才华  -此话怎讲
- A bit of my talent.. - Oh? How so?
那场扑克牌  你放水让贝克特赢
The poker game. You let Beckett win.
我不晓得你乱说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
别装了  我看了你的牌
Come on. I checked your cards.
我  我不想在她所有朋友的面前
I- I didn't want to take her money
赢光她的钱
In front of all her friends.
凯特·贝克特不是那种
Kate Beckett is not some bimbo
需要宽大臂膀保护的女人
who needs big, strong you to look out for her.
她是个真正的女人
She's a real woman.
一个真正的女人是  不需要人刻意保护的
And a real woman does not want to be patronized.
她是对的  老爸
- She's right, dad. - Yeah..
我只是好意
I was being nice.
卡塞尔  好的  我马上到
Castle. Yeah, I'm on my way
好的  我这就回局里
All right, I'm on my way
看看这个玛塔·哈莉到底是谁
To the precinct to find out Who this Mata Hari really was.
艾莉森·高德曼的邮箱帐号
Allison Goldman e-mail account..
艾莉森写道
Allison writes:
"李  这周我们换到周二见好吗"
"Lee, can we meet on tuesday instead this week?"
李回复  "可以  老地方见"
Lee writes back,  "sounds good. The usual place."
周二  就是她被害的那天
Tuesday. The day that she was murdered.
这么说来  我们假想的艾莉森男友
So Allison's imaginary boyfriend has a very real e-mail account.
还真有一个邮箱账号
He goes by the screen
账户名为"LWax220"
Name "LWax220".
她丈夫说没听过这个名字
The husband said it didn't sound familiar to him.
我们通过网络查出来了
We cyber-Tracked it down.
卡塞尔  看  这个人是个作家
Check this Castle.. The guy's a writer.
一个真正的作家
A real writer or
还是上过写作培训课的写手
an "i took a course at the learning annex" writer?
他的名字叫李·瓦克斯
Well, his name is Lee Wax.
他是纪实犯罪的作家
He writes true crime.
《短袜与鲜血》
"Bobby Socks and blood..."
"拉拉队长和雄鹰童子军的真实故事"
"The true story of a cheerleader and eagle scout
"震惊全美的凶杀案"
And the murder that shocked america".
-得了吧  -或许他厌倦了
- Gimme a break. - Well, maybe he got tired of
描写他人的谋杀
Writing about other people's murders
转而自己作案
And decided to commit one on his own.
这是什么
What's this?
这是那天晚上你赢的钱
Your winnings from the other night.
我不傻
I'm not an idiot.
早知道你故意输的
I know you threw the last hand.
你怎么看出来的
How did you figure it out?
这不是重点
That's not the point.
我妈妈告诉你的  对吧
Oh, my mother called you, didn't she?
我们得再赌一次
You owe me a rematch.
没问题  我奉陪
Fine. You wanna play? Let's play.
明晚就比怎么样
How about tomorrow night?
-和你那帮神秘哥们一起  -别开玩笑了
- With your mystery buddies? - What, are you kidding?
不行  他们会活活吃掉你
No, no, no, those guys would eat you alive.
不如找些本地的人
No, I was thinking of something a little more local.
我在哥谭市的[蝙蝠侠中的城市]  合作伙伴
My, uh, Gotham City crew.
和他们一起我比较放得开
Guys I beat on a regular basis.
-你在哥谭市的伙伴  -有队长和市长
- Your Gotham City crew. - Yeah, the Captain, the Mayor
还有马克维法官
And Judge Markway.
即你的老板  你老板的老板
You know, your boss, your boss' boss
还有授权令的签署人
And the guy that signs your warrants.
这些人让你觉得紧张了吧
Or would that make you nervous?
不是有意向你施加压力
I mean, I wouldn't want to throw your game.
也不是故意拍你马屁
But I also don't want you to feel patronized.
放马过来  我会打得你满地找牙
Just set it up and prepare to get your ass kicked.
有人吗
Hello?
他们竟然被跟踪
Look who's stalking.
呆着别动
Stay here.
-你是谁  -你是谁
- Hey! Who the hell are you? - Who the hell are you?
李·瓦克斯  你们在我家做什么
Lee Wax. What are you doing in my apartment?
-你是女的  -再不报上姓名
- You're a woman. - Either you tell me who you are right now,
我马上报警
Or I am calling the cops.
我就是警察  探长凯特·贝克特
I am the cops. My name is Detective Kate Beckett.
警方将询问你一些
We would like to ask you some questions
-有关艾莉森·高德曼的问题  -艾莉森
- About Allison Goldman. - Allison.
等等
Just...
我  马上联系一下律师
Just, uh, let me get my lawyer.
为什么联系律师
Why do you need a lawyer?
你自己想想
Why do you think?
你有需要招供的事情
So you're confessing.
当然没有  只不过
No, I'm not confessing to anything. It's just...
出版商告诫我  除非律师在场
My publisher instructed me not to talk to law enforcemen
-不要谈论任何法律案件  -出版商
- Until I had a lawyer present.. - Your publisher?
我会在口供里声明
You know, I would like to state for the record
我既没有窝藏罪犯  也没有隐匿案情
That I never harbored, nor did I conceal, a fugitive.
-你在说些什么  -艾莉森·高德曼
- What are you talking about? - Allison Goldman.
你们找上门来  肯定是发现她的行踪了
If that's why you're here, then obviously you found her.
没错  发现她被谋杀
Yes. Murdered.
谋杀
Murdered?
谁杀了她
Murdered by who?
鉴于你对她病态的迷恋
Well, given your unhealthy obsession for her,
我觉得你有很大嫌疑
I'm going to take a wild stab at... you.
我
Me?
我就是一个代笔者
No, I am a ghostwriter.
-代笔替她写回忆录  -回忆录
- We were working on her memoir. - Memoir?
艾莉森·高德曼为什么需要回忆录
Why would Allison Goldman need a memoir?
你们不清楚她的真实身份
Wait. So you don't know who she really is?
现在知道了
We do now.
看来  威彻斯特的家庭主妇
Apparently, our Westchester housewife
还是一个在逃犯
Was also a fugitive.
这是艾莉森·高德曼
That's Allison Goldman?
又名欣西亚·德恩
A.K.A. Cynthia Dern.
1989年伙同两个朋友
In 1989, she and two friends
在属于石油公司的油轮上安装炸弹
Set off a bomb on a tanker  owned by a big oil company.
我记得这个案子  一些激进的环保主义者
I remember this. Some radical environmentalists
强烈抗议埃克森·瓦尔迪兹号邮轮泄漏事故
Protesting the "Exxon Valdez" spill.
一人死亡一人被捕
Yes. One was killed, one was caught.
不过欣西亚·德恩仍在逃
But Cynthia Dern was never found.
看来她还是没有逃脱往日的罪行
Looks like her past finally caught up with her.
贾内德·斯万斯托制造炸弹
Jared Swanstrom, uh, built the bomb.
苏珊·梅勒和欣西亚负责上船安装
Susan Mailer and Cynthia snuck onboard to set it,
但出了差错
Only something went wrong.
船上本应空无一人  没有载油
You see, the ship was supposed to be empty of oil and people,
但是船长山姆·派克中途回到船上
But the captain, Sam Pike, had come back.
在爆炸中瘫痪
He was paralyzed in the explosion.
你是如何查到欣西亚下落
How did you track down Cynthia?
不是我  是她找到我
I didn't. She contacted me.
欣西亚准备自首了
Cynthia had decided to turn herself in,
但投降之前
But before she surrendered,
希望将这一切公之于众
She wanted to get her story out  to the public
同时表达深深的忏悔
And express her remorse.
借此拉拢民众
And get public opinion on her side.
对潜在陪审团成员来说  这很奏效
It's a great way to influence a potential jury pool.
但她的确犯了错误对吗
But she did it, right?
她打算如何引导舆论
So how was she planning on influencing them?
欣西亚告诉我
Cynthia told me that
爆炸当晚  她曾想放弃
On the night of the bombing, she had tried to back out.
因为意识到船长还在上面
When she realized that the captain was aboard,
她提议取消活动
She argued with Susan Mailer to call it off,
但是苏珊拒绝了
But Susan refused.
争吵之后苏珊自行安装了炸弹
Susan went to set the bomb herself
却在爆炸中身亡  很讽刺吧
And ironically, died in the explosion.
欣西亚则销声匿迹
She was vaporized.
为什么她又出现在公众视线
So why would she come out of hiding now?
她需要钱
Money. She need the cash.
你付钱给她
You were paying her?
如果回忆录畅销  一周能有几百元
A couple hundred a week. If the book had sold well...
具体数字尚不方便透露
I don't have to tell you how much money was at stake.
你最后一次见到她是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Cynthia?
周二下午
Tuesday afternoon.
她有没有提过要去见谁
Did she mention that she was going to see anyone else,
或许是她从前生活中的人
Maybe someone from her past?
没有  她对此相当敏感
No, no, Cynthia was really paranoid about
不希望书籍出版之前被指认
Being discovered before the book came out.
也不许我联系她过去生活中的人
She didn't want me to get in touch with anyone from her old life.
不过你还是联系了
But you did, anyway..
要对得起罪案作家这个名号
Any true crime writer worth their salt
消息一定要可靠
Is gonna check her story with other sources.
没错  我是打了几通电话
Okay, so I made a few calls.
你联系的这些人中
The sources that you were talking to,
有没有想置她于死地的
Did any of them want her dead?
也许有  不过
Maybe, but...
别忘了  没人找得到她
Remember, nobody knew how to find her.
连我都不知道她住在哪里
I mean,i didn't even know where she lived.
我需要看看你的采访记录
I'm gonna need to see your interview notes
还有回忆录的原稿
And your manuscript.
需要材料尽管拿  不过作为回报
You can have whatever you want, but in return
我希望对调查过程全程跟踪
I'd like to be kept in the loop as the investigation proceeds.
为什么
What for?
-为了完成我的书  -你还要继续写完
- My book. - You're gonna go through with it?
欣西亚已经死了
But Cynthia's dead.
错  欣西亚被谋杀了
Correction, Cynthia was murdered,
因此她的回忆录
Which means her memoir
就变成罪案文学了
Just became a true crime story,
这正是我的强项
Which is kind of my forte.
你们可真是帮了大忙了
You'd be doing me a huge favor.
我也很想帮忙
You know, I- I would love to.
不过有一大群作家在我周围
But I have a whole list of writers
等着捡便宜
Who are hanging around, looking for favors.
所以  谢谢合作
So thank you very much, though, for cooperating, and I'll...
有消息我会私下再联系你
Catch you on the dark side.
这份兼职真不错
It's a pretty sweet gig
卡塞尔先生  很会利用外部条件
You've scored for yourself, Mr. Castle.
这就是成为畅销作家的秘密武器吧
Is this your secret to writing best sellers?
跟着漂亮女警官
Follow the pretty cop lady around
趁机得到详实丰富的资料
And take copious notes?
我的天份也起了一定作用
I like to think talent played a small part.
不过  能在警局和现场畅行无阻
Still, this is the kind of all-access pass
的确是作家梦寐以求的
Most writers would kill for.
直说你想干什么吧
Let's get to the part where you tell me what you want.
你给我打电话好了
Well, maybe you can give me a call sometime...
作家对作家
One professional to another.
是不是这件事也要上报女领导
Or do you need to check with your boss lady?
不如你把号码给我
Why don't you give me your number,
让我考虑一下  怎么样
And I'll see what I can do?
恐怖分子收集折价券过生活
A domestic terrorist who clips coupons.
多好的电影素材
I just might buy the movie rights myself.
显然爆炸装置
Well, the bombing obviously wasn't
不是很复杂
A very sophisticated operation.
苏珊·梅勒在爆炸中身亡
Susan Mailer was killed in the blast,
随后贾内德·斯万斯托被联调局逮捕
And Jared Swanstrom was caught by the FBI
被关押十五年
And served 15 years.
艾莉森·高德曼又名欣西亚·德恩
Allison Goldman, a.k.a Cynthia Dern
几乎逃亡二十年
Managed to stay a fugitive for nearly two decades.
最近刚刚暴露身份
And then she poked her head out of hiding,
几个月后  她就死了
And a couple months later, she's dead.
谁会将一份怨恨埋藏二十年
Well, who would hold a grudge for 20 years?
那些被她毁了下半辈子的人
How about the people whose lives she's ruined?
你说她住在欧文顿
You say she was living in Irvington?
离这只有几英里
That's just a couple of miles away from here.
死前几个月
In the months leading up to her death,
欣西亚曾和一名记者一起写作
Cynthia was working with a journalist.
我们和李·瓦克斯聊过几次
We spoke with Lee Wax several times.
从没提到和欣西亚有关
She never told us Cynthia was involved.
她应该告诉我们
She should have.
劳驾  失陪了
Excuse me, will you? Excuse me, please.
这对他来说很艰难
This is hard for him.
对那件事他仍然很愤怒  我们全家都是
He's still angry about what happened. We all are.
这是你儿子
This your son?
亚当
Adam.
-和老爸一样做了海员  -安置费不够支付
- He's a sailor, just like his dad. - The settlement wasn't enough to
山姆全部医疗费用
Cover all of Sam's medical costs.
亚当从十几岁开始
Adam's been working and helping out
就一直工作来贴补家用
Since he was a teenager.
亚当  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Adam? I'm detective Kate Beckett.
是跟那个人有关吗
Is this about her?
欣西亚  艾莉森  或她随便编的名字
Cynthia or Allison or whatever she called herself?
你知道她就住在附近吗
Did you have any idea that she lived so close?
不知道  也不想知道
Didn't know, didn't care.
你对这个差点杀了你父亲的
You didn't care about the woman
女人无动于衷
Who almost killed your father?
我认为这不可理喻
I find that hard to believe.
我们全家苦等二十年
You know, my family waited 20 years
就为了等欣西亚·德恩被捕
For the cops to find Cynthia Dern
我父亲借此伸张一点正义
So my dad could get just a little bit of justice.
但二十年也太长了  一切都晚了
Well, it's too late for that now.
你们到底来做什么
So what do you want from us?
只是以为你们想知道  欣西亚怎么死的
Well, I thought you might want to know how Cynthia died.
淹死在机油里
She was drowned in motor oil.
机油
Motor oil?
几乎可以确定  杀死她的人
It's almost as if whoever did it
曾和爆炸事件有直接关系
had a personal connection to the bombing.
亚当  你的车库里
Adam, if I looked in your garage right now,
是否有机油
Would I find motor oil?
探长  我有一艘船和一辆车
I own a boat and a car, detective.
上周二你在哪里
And where were you last tuesday?
我每周二都在曼彻斯特一家烧烤店做酒保
I bartend at the Foxtail Grill on Manchester every tuesday.
还有什么要问的
Are we done?
目前没有
Yes, for now.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗
You know what?
我希望他的不在场证明成立
I hope his alibi checks out.
希望不是他做的
I hope he didn't do it.
那时估计你就会说
And here I thought you would be saying
要的确是他做的  该是多么精彩的故事啊
What a great story it would make if Adam Pike did it..
-子报父仇  -这个素材真的不错
- A son taking revenge for his father. - It is a good story. It's a great story.
从个人角度  我只想给这家人大团圆结局
Personally, I would just write a happier ending for that family.
这是89年油轮爆炸事件后  联调局的档案
FBI files on the tanker bombing in '89
-看完之后我发现  -请说
- I've been going through them. - And?
爆炸三天后贾内德·斯万斯托
Three days after the bombing, they captured Jared Swanstrom
在藏身的汽车旅馆中被捕
At a motel where he'd been hiding out.
警方收到消息  有人打来电话
Feds had a tip line. Some helpful citizen calls
说在汽车旅馆里看到斯万斯托
And said they'd seen Swanstrom at the motel.
联邦警探轻而易举抓住了他
Feds go in, grab him up, easy peasy.
这是正常流程
It's pretty standard stuff.
对  不过奇怪的是
Yeah, until you get to the part where
线人从未现身领取奖励
The tipster never collects onthe reward.
线人是谁
And who was the tipster?
没了  联调局也不知道
That's just it. The FBI never knew
-她是匿名打的电话  -她
- 'cause she didn't leave a name. - She?
记录显示  是一名年轻女性
Records describe the voice as young and female.
也许是欣西亚·德恩
It could be Cynthia Dern.
你认为她会向警方出卖同伙
Do you think she would give up her friends to the cops?
我的看法不重要
Doesn't matter what I think.
斯万斯托是否也有此想法
It only matters what Swanstrom thought.
入狱十五年
The guy did 15 years in prison.
有足够时间想清谁背叛了他
That's a long time to think about who put you there.
- Jared Swanstrom? - 怎么?
- Jared swanstrom? - Yeah?
纽约员警 我们想问你一些有关Cynthia Dern的问题
NYPD. We'd like to ask you some questions about cynthia dern
呃 我不知道有什么好说的
Well, i'm not sure what i can tell you.
我有20年没见到她了
I haven't seen her in 20 years.
可你知道她在写一本书 对吧?
But you knew she was writing a book, right?
- 你跟Lee Wax谈过  - 我是跟她谈了
- You spoke to lee wax.  - I spoke with her.
- 我...我托她问候Cynthia - 这么说 你并没有怀恨在心喽?
- I- I told her to give cynthia my regards. - So you weren't bearing any old grudges?
对欣西亚吗  为什么
Against Cynthia? What for?
把你弄到局子里
For turning you in.
你被捕的那晚是欣西亚打的电话
It was Cynthia who called the cops the night you were arrested.
就算这样  那她打电话也是为了自救
Well, if that's true, she was just trying to save herself.
爆炸之后  欣西亚想逃跑
Right after the bombing, Cynthia wanted to run..
跑到加拿大
You know, try to make it to canada.
但是我崩溃了
But I, uh, I fell apart.
为什么
Why?
内心谴责  是我造了炸弹
Guilt. I'm the one who built the bomb.
-但是我搞砸了  -怎么讲
- I'm the one who messed it up. - Messed it up how?
女孩子们本该有三分钟时间
The girls were supposed to have three minutes
趁爆炸前下船
To get off that ship before it went off..
三分钟
Three minutes.
那天晚上欣西亚回到车上说
When Cynthia got back in the car that night,
事情有点不对
She said that something had gone wrong,
炸弹提早  提早爆炸了
That the bomb had.. had blown early.
苏珊·梅勒是因为我才死的
I'm the reason that Susan Mailer is dead.
至少他们中有个人
At least one of them took responsibility
肯对那晚上的事情负责
For what happened that night.
没准他负的责任太多了
Yeah. Maybe even a little too much responsibility.
你不相信贾内德·斯万斯托的话
You don't believe Jared Swanstrom's story?
其实是这样
Well, that's the thing
不是他的话  而是欣西亚的话
It's not his story. It's Cynthia's.
你们想破坏了享用美酒的心情吗
You wanna break it down for those of us who've already had a glass of wine?
欣西亚告诉李·瓦克斯她曾与苏珊·梅勒争论
Cynthia told Lee Wax that she and Susan Mailer had an argument as to
是否明知船长在船上仍引爆炸弹
whether or not to set off the bomb once they knew the captain was onboard.
欣西亚不干了
Cynthia backed out.
苏珊于是独自引爆炸弹  于是
Susan went on to set off the bomb by herself and...
爆炸了
... Boom.
但今天  贾内德·斯万斯托说欣西亚
But today, Jared Swanstrom said  that Cynthia
告诉他爆炸时机不对
told him there was something wrong with the timer.
她对争执一事只字不提
She never said anything about an argument.
这可是一个明显的疑点
Oh... Well, that is a rather glaring omission.
当我创作时
You know, when I'm writing,
发现一切都和选择有关
I find it's all about choices..
哪些该讲述  哪些该省略
What to put in, what to leave out,
何时揭示真相  何时埋下伏笔
When to reveal some information, when to hold something back.
然而作为代笔人  你只知道
But as someone else's ghostwriter, you only know
别人想让你知道的
What they want you to know.
所以李·瓦克斯  不是欣西亚的代笔人吗
But Lee Wax isn't Cynthia's ghostwriter anymore, right?
现如今她死了  这已不是回忆录
Now that she's dead, it's no longer a memoir.
而是一个真实发生的罪案
It's a true crime story.
听起来真实发生的事情
And it sounds like the true story
这一切比欣西亚的谎言更引人入胜
Is a whole lot juicier than Cynthia's lies.
早上好
Good morning. Oh. Hey.
对不起  我刚刚
Sorry. I've just...
正在看李·瓦克斯的访谈笔记
Been going over Lee Wax's interview notes.
她跟贾内德·斯万斯托交谈时
When she spoke to Jared Swanstrom,
他所说的和他告诉我们的一样
He told her the same thing he told us.
欣西亚说炸弹爆炸早了
Cynthia said the bomb blew early,
但是她把没把这一段放在书里
But she left that version out of her book.
是因为这和欣西亚最近的讲述矛盾
That's because it contradicted Cynthia's latest story,
两个女孩争论之际发现
That the girls argued when they discovered
船长仍在船上
That captain Pike was still onboard
苏珊于是独自引爆了炸弹
And that Susan set the bomb alone.
根据出版商
According to the publisher,
李·瓦克斯所写须经欣西亚批准
Cynthia has full approval over everything Lee Wax wrote.
不听她的就得滚蛋
It was her way or the highway.
你跟出版商谈过吗
You talked to the publisher?
我正巧认识圈子里的人
I am... somewhat known in those circles.
不论怎样  他们不喜欢这样
Anyway, they didn't like it.
他们要的是一个真实的犯罪自白
They were looking for a true crime tell-all,
而他们拿到的则是
And what they were getting was some
毫无卖点的悔过书
sanitized bunch of remorseful boohooing
他们本准备终止出版
They were getting ready to pull the plug.
现在呢
And now?
现在欣西亚的凶杀满城风雨
Well, now that Cynthia's murder  is all over the media,
他们准备重新包装
They're back onboard,
只要从更有轰动效应的角度切入
So long as the book takes a more sensationalized angle..
"真实血案
"Kaboom! The true story
国内恐怖分子化身市郊主妇
Of a domestic terrorist turned suburban housewife
震惊全国"
And the crime that shocked America."
-抓人眼球  -谢谢
- Catchy. - Thanks.
既然欣西亚不在了
So with Cynthia out of the way,
李·瓦克斯有机会成为畅销作家
Lee Wax is sitting on a potential best seller.
杀人的原因可没有那么复杂
People have killed for a lot less.
好的  带他进来
All right, bring him in.
怎么了
What?
亚当·派克的不在场证明被推翻了
Adam Pike's alibi fell apart.
周二晚上他实际并未工作
He was lying about being at work on tuesday night.
我没有杀她
I didn't kill her.
我甚至不知她在哪
I didn't even know where she was.
如果你继续撒谎我可帮不了你
We're not gonna get anywhere if you keep lying to me.
我知道你去了威彻斯特
I know you went to Westchester.
我跟欣西亚的丈夫谈过  他记得
I spoke to Cynthia's husband.  He remembers
看到一个像你的人  在案发几周前
Seeing a guy just like you outside their house,
在他家屋外出没
A couple weeks before she was murdered.
别逼我把你列为嫌犯
Don't make me put you in the lineup.
我只是
I just...
想跟她谈谈
Wanted to talk to her.
-你怎么找到她的  -那个作家
- How'd you find her? - That writer.
她谈起我爸的事  那种语气
The way she kept talking about what happened to my dad..
那些事  只有在场的人才知道
She knew things that only someone on that ship could know.
所以我
So I...
跟踪她
Started following her around.
最终  我跟着找到了欣西亚·德恩
Eventually, she led me to Cynthia Dern.
你为什么不报警
And why didn't you call the police?
因为我想直视她的眼睛
Because I wanted to look her in the eye.
我想告诉她  她做的都是徒劳的
I wanted to tell her none of it mattered.
休想用她沾满鲜血的钱换来宽恕
Her blood money wouldn't buy our forgiveness.
什么钱
What money?
什么叫沾满鲜血的钱
What do you mean by "blood money"?
在我发现欣西亚的住处
After I found out where Cynthia lived
我告诉了我妈妈
I went and told my mom.
我不知道是否该打给联调局还是谁
I didn't know if we should call the feds or what.
她开始啜泣
She started crying.
她告诉我从爆炸那天起
She told me we'd been getting money
每个月会收到一笔钱
every month since the bombing different amounts..
时多时少
Sometimes more, sometimes less..
但是月月未落
But every month.
她认为钱是欣西亚·德恩寄来的
And she thought that the money was coming from Cynthia Dern?
第一封信  有一张条子
The first envelope, there was a note.
"请原谅我"
"Please forgive me."
苏珊·梅勒死了
Susan Mailer was dead.
斯万斯托在蹲监狱
Swanstrom was in prison.
不可能会是别人
There wasn't anybody else.
你知道  凭你所言
You know, with this kind of evidence,
我们本可在好几年前逮捕欣西亚
Cynthia could've been caught years ago.
妈妈说  没有那笔钱
Mom said without that money,
我们娘俩撑不下来
We wouldn't have made it,
她自认为只要欣西亚逍遥法外
And she figured, as long as Cynthia was free,
钱就会一直寄来
The money would keep coming.
那为什么要骗我们上周二你在工作
So why did you lie to me about where you were last tuesday?
因为我在犯罪现场
Because I was there.
我在酒店  我跟踪她来着
At the hotel. I followed her.
我本要跟她谈谈
Look, I was just gonna talk to her.
整整一个小时  我在楼梯间踱步
I spent an hour walking up and down that hallway,
想着能鼓起勇气敲门
Trying to get up the courage to go and knock on that door.
我本要这么做
You know, i- I was gonna do it.
但是有别人下了电梯  敲了她的门
But then someone got off the elevator and knocked on her door instead.
你看到了杀她的人吗
You saw her killer?
没看清  但是我听到了他们的对话
I didn't get a good look, but I did hear them talking.
-我能告诉你一件事  -什么
- And I can tell you one thing. - What?
是一个女人
It was a woman.
李·瓦克斯
Lee Wax.
贝克特
Beckett!
是李·瓦克斯
It was Lee Wax!
贝克特
Beckett!
李·瓦克斯
Lee Wax!
李
Lee...
谋杀  你们脑子有毛病吗
Murder. Are you people crazy?
有目击证人证明你在旅店
I have an eyewitness who can place you at the S.R.O.
欣西亚尸体被发现的地方
Where Cynthia's body was found.
你有动机  方式  和机会
You had motive, means andopportunity.
拜托  也只有小说家
Please. Only a novelist
能编出这么离奇的故事
Could come up with a twist this absurd.
可不如为抢救自己的小说
Not as absurd as killing a woman to salvage your story.
把她溺死在机油里
Drowning her in motor oil
而更加离奇吧
Gave you just the ending you need.
我是个真实罪案记录作家
I'm a true crime writer
并没什么编故事的天分
So I don't have your talent for fiction.
我们知道出版商想撤回出版合同
We know your publisher wanted to dump your contract.
那是因为我告诉他们
Because I told them
我认为欣西亚撒谎
that I thought Cynthia was lying.
你不认为她的悔过是发自内心的吗
So you didn't believe her remorse was genuine?
当欣西亚哭时  全是为了自己
When Cynthia cried, it was for herself.
用悔过的眼泪换点钱
She wanted to cash in
再帮自己离开监狱  仅此而已
And keep herself out of jail. That's it.
她一定觉得自己该为那天发生的事负责吧
Well, she must've felt some responsibility for what happened.
毕竟  她每年都给派克一家寄钱
After all, she sent the Pikes money year after year..
什么钱
What money?
从爆炸发生后的每个月
Every month since the bombing,
派克一家一直收到钱
The Pikes have been receiving money
来自欣西亚·德恩的一点好意
Courtesy of Cynthia Dern.
你的笔记里可无丝毫涉及
Only, there's nothing about that in your notes.
因为她从没提过  你们确定吗
Because she never told me.  Are you sure?
确定
We're sure.
欣西亚被杀的那个周二
Look, the tuesday that Cynthia was killed,
我和我的出版商正在吃饭
I was out to dinner with my publisher
一直到午夜
Until after midnight,
所以我没法杀她
So I couldn't have killed her.
如果我要决定写回忆录
Remind me, if I ever decide to write a memoir,
千万阻止我
To never write a memoir.
好
Okay.
为什么呢
Why not?
因为回忆录是真实的故事
Because memoirs are about truth.
而我并不是一个实话实说的人
And I'm not a very truthful person.
我很容易把自己写成好人
It would be too easy to make myself look good.
可能没有你想的那么容易
It might be harder than you think..
也许
Maybe.
但是我会从
But I would sure start
我曾经做过最慷慨的事开始
With the most generous thing I ever did.
你是说
You mean,
例如因为你对自己的罪行十分内疚
Like how you anonymously sent money to your victims
所以匿名给受害者寄钱
Because you felt so guilty about what you'd done?
欣西亚写回忆录的目的
The object of Cynthia's memoir
在于博得同情
Was to gain sympathy.
能有什么比给派克家
What could be more sympathetic
坚持寄钱20年更值得同情呢
Than sending the Pikes guilt money for 20 years?
可欣西亚没告诉李·瓦克斯  这点说不通啊
It doesn't make sense that Cynthia didn't tell Lee Wax.
除非钱不是来自欣西亚
A meno che il denaro non venisse da Cynthia.
肯定是欣西亚寄的
It had to be from Cynthia.
斯万斯托在监狱  苏珊·梅勒死了
Swanstrom was  in prison and Susan Mailer was dead.
跟  你们确定没有其他人了吗
Call. And you're sure no one else was involved?
没  只有他们三个有可能
No, just the three of 'em,
如果你信任联调局
Assuming you believe the FBI.
跟
Call.
我们不用非得讨论这个吧
You know, we don't really have to talk about this.
还有不要提及他对于
Anything to stop his honour here
预算倡议的支持
From talking bout budget initiatives.
好吧法官  谁刚跟你对着干来着
Okay, judge.  Who was it that appointed you again?
我信联调局  但为何对欣西亚·德恩
Now the FBI believe.  But why take Cynthia Dern's word
关于爆炸那天的事情深信不疑呢
for anything that happened the night of the bombing
甚至她的写手都不信任她
When her own ghostwriter didn't even trust her?
法官是对的
You know, the judge is right.
我们到底知道多少真实情况
What do we actually know about what happened?
还真不多
Not much.
根据李·瓦克斯的笔记
According to Lee Wax's notes,
派克船长在爆炸之前
Captain Pike heard two women arguing
听到了两个女人争执
Just before the explosion,
而欣西亚又说
And Cynthia claims that
她那时正试图改变苏珊的主意
she was trying to change Susan's mind.
不跟
Fold.
但如果我们假设欣西亚在撒谎
But if we assume Cynthia was lying..
那么就是苏珊想救派克
Then maybe it was Susan that wanted to save Pikeke
而欣西亚想溜
And Cynthia that wanted to run.
加注20美金
Raise $20.
对  但是炸弹已经安置好了
Right. But the bomb was already set,
而三分倒时已开始了
So the 3-minute timer is already ticking.
女孩们争执  浪费宝贵的时间
The girls argue, wasting precious seconds...
苏珊朝正倒计时的炸弹跑去
Susan runs towards the ticking bomb
想把它关了
To try to shut it down...
而欣西亚跑去找掩护保命
While Cynthia runs for cover.
苏珊向炸弹跑去  但是来不及了
Right. Susan gets to the bomb, but too late. Boom.
就是说
Which means
苏珊·梅勒不是因引发爆炸而死
Susan Mailer didn't die trying to set the bomb.
而是为了救那个无辜的船长而死
She died trying to save an innocent man's life.
不跟
Fold.
可这仍旧解释不了钱是谁寄的
It still doesn't explain where the money came from.
不跟
Fold.
卡塞尔  这是怎么回事  你最擅长诡计
Well, what about it, Castle? You're good with twists.
说说钱从哪儿来的
Where'd the money come from?
我在想呢
I'm thinking.
没错  你大概在想是否继续跟
Yeah, well, you might want to think up some chips for the pot,
好像就剩下你和我啦
'Cause it looks like it's just you and me.
好吧  贝克特探长  我全押
All right, detective Beckett.. - I'm all in.
怎么  看到真刀真枪害怕了
Oh, what's the matter? You afraid of a little action?
探长  帮帮忙  让他输个精光
Oh, do us a favor, detective. Beat his pants off.
有胆量的话  拜托让我输个精光
Yes, please, beat my pants off, if you dare.
贝克特  替我争口气
Beckett, do me proud.
争气啊  让这家伙哭得像个小姑娘
To hell with proud, make him cry like a little girl.
好吧
All right.
伙计们  抱歉  我今天手气不好
Sorry, fellas, it's just not my night.
看看谁是乖孩子
Oh, who's a good little boy?
谁是乖孩子呢
Who's a good little boy?
你  你  还有你都是
You are and you are and you are.
卡塞尔  老赢不烦吗
Don't you ever get tired of winning, Castle?
你觉得赢钱烦吗  反正我不觉得
You'd think so, right? But no.
好啦  我要撤了
Well, I think that's it for me.
探长  能和你玩牌很愉快
Detective, it was a pleasure.
我也是  市长先生
Mr. Mayor.
抱歉  没能帮你们把案子破了
Sorry we couldn't solve your case.
我也很抱歉  没找让他哭得像小姑娘
And I'm sorry I couldn't make him cry like a little girl..
探长  这不能怪你
Mm. Well, it's not your fault, detective.
无论他牌运怎么差  总能设法咸鱼翻身
No matter how down he gets, he always manages to rise from the dead.
-诡计在这里呢  -什么诡计
- Oh, now that'd be a twist. - What?
伊万斯托还在坐牢
The money had to come from Cynthia
所以钱只能是欣西亚寄的
Because Swanstrom was in jail
而且苏珊·梅勒已经死了  对吗
And Susan Mailer was dead, right?
没错
Right.
可如果那次爆炸中苏珊·梅勒没被炸死呢
But what if Susan Mailer didn't die in that explosion?
如果她还尚在人间呢
What if she's still alive?
苏珊·梅勒还活着
Susan Mailer? Alive?
她的尸体一直没找到
Her body was never found.
因为她在爆炸中人间蒸发了
Yeah, because she was vaporized in the explosion.
也许她只是被炸伤了
Well, maybe she was thrown clear.
她受到重度烧伤  需要救治
And she would been  badly burned and would've need care.
可在本地医院里
And no one matching her description
并没有与她情况相符的医疗记录
Ever checked into area hospitals.
好兄弟  再挖点细节出来
Mere details, my good man.
听着  我们这里称其为  事实
Um, around here we call them "facts."
好吧  那让我们多找些事实出来
Well, then let's go get us some facts.
请不要因此瞧不起我
Please don't think less of me.
我这么做只为了生存
I did what I had to do to survive.
这些钱从不同的地方寄来
These are from all over the place.
这些不是最近寄来的
Uh, not the recent ones
最近寄来的都出自同一地址
The recent ones are all the same.
利帝兹  宾西法尼亚州
Lititz, Pennsylvania.
跑长途前  我得上个厕所
If we're gonna road-Trip, I'm gonna have to pee first.
-从来没见过这女人  -能肯定吗
- I've never seen her before. - Are you positive?
-他的口气像不肯定吗  -卡塞尔
- Didn't he sound positive? - Castle.
好吧
Okay.
这个女人呢
How about her?
-她现在应该老了些  -老多少
- She'd be older now. - How much older?
20岁
20 years.
没见过
I don't think so.
听个神秘小说家的话  就这个结果
That's what I get for listening to a mystery writer.
-她可能现在有伤疤或跛脚
She might have scars or walk with a limp.
像出过什么意外吗
Like she's been in an accident?
可能是玛丽·莱特
It could be Mary Wright.
玛丽·莱特
Mary Wright?
她每个月来一次  我想是她
She comes in once a month or so.
每次来给纽约的亲戚汇款
Buys a money order to send to her relatives in new york.
你有她的家庭住址吗
Do you have her address?
这么说可能有点天真  但是
It sounds naive now, but, um...
当年  我那么做是因为
Everything I did back then I did because
我当时认为那是种帮助
I thought it would help.
苏珊我们今天找你来  不是想说爆炸的事
We're not here because of the bombing, Susan.
我们要听的是  你对欣西亚·德恩做的事
We're here because of what you did to Cynthia Dern.
尸体是在盛满机油的浴缸里  被人发现的
Her body was found in a tub of motor oil.
看来你已经知道了
But you already know that.
在我们谈话的同时  法证科也在调查这起案件
Forensics is going through that room as we speak.
我敢肯定  他们会找到蛛丝马迹
And believe me, they will find something,
证明你与欣西亚的死有关系
Something that connects you to Cynthia's death.
那种陈年旧事  她本不应该再提起
She should've just left it all alone.
她嫁了人  生活幸福
She had a husband and a good life.
可欣西亚不甘心过那种生活
But that wasn't Cynthia.
一旦她决心做什么事
Once she decided on something,
周围人最好乖乖让开路
Well, you just better not be in her way.
就像那晚在油轮上是吗
Like that night on the tanker?
我看到船长走下来
I saw the captain go below.
可不知怎么他半路折回  我们没发现
I don't know how he got back onboard without us seeing.
我本想
I- I tried...
可我  太迟啦
But I was.. I was too late.
炸弹爆炸时  我被弹出了甲板
When the bomb exploded, I was thrown overboard.
我还能感觉到  热浪腐灼着皮肤
I can still feel the heat on my skin...
到今天都忘不了
Even today.
没去医院  你是怎么活下来的
How did you survive without medical attention?
有个朋友收留我
Um, a friend took me in.
有位医学院的学生照顾我  直到我完全康复
A- A med student nursed me back to health.
-我弄到个新身份  -变成了玛丽·莱特
- I got a new identity. - And Mary Wright was born.
如果所有人都以为你死了
It's not hard to live like a ghost
你就不会过得那么艰难
When everyone you love thinks you're dead.a.
从此断绝了与所有认识人的联系
I never contacted anyone from my former life...
连父母都没联系过
Not even my parents.
可你一直给派克家寄钱
But you still sent money to the Pikes.
他有个儿子  需要医疗费
They had a son... medical bills.
我有责任这么做
I- I was responsible.
本来一切可以相安无事  可是
Everything could've stayed just the way it was except...
可是  欣西亚要出书
Except Cynthia decided to write a book..
那个记者在环境版上发了个帖子
That reporter put a post on an environmental board
询问欣西亚的情况
Asking for info on Cynthia.
我以组织老成员的身份  写了封电子邮件
I e-mailed, pretending to be an old friend of the group.
时日不多  我就发现
It didn't take long for me to figure out
那记者已经找到欣西亚
That she had found Cynthia and
而欣西亚就船上发生的事说了谎
Cynthia was lying about what happened on the ship.
你找到她  和她对质
You tracked her down. You confronted her.
我威胁她  如果写本书
I threatened to turn myself in
我就去自首
If she went through with the book..
把所有的事情全抖出来
Give myself up, tell the authorities everything.
她恳求要先见见我
She begged to meet with me first..
找个地方谈谈
Somewhere we could talk.
所以你租下那个房间
That's when you rented the room?
不是我  欣西亚租的房间
Oh, no, Cynthia rented the room, not me.
-那是她计划里的一部分  -她的计划
- It was all part of her plan. - Her plan?
她计划要杀我
Her plan to murder me.
等我到那里  她递来一杯酒
W- When I got there, she poured me a drink.
嘴里说  为老友干杯
"Let's toast to old friends," she said.
只不过  我不喝酒
Only, you see, I don't drink.
我想走  可她不让
I tried to leave. She wouldn't let me.
我就躲进了盥洗室
I- I hid in the bathroom.
知道我看见什么了
That's when I saw it...
满满一浴缸的油
The tub, full of oil.
我一下子明白过来
Then I understood.
她就没想找你谈
She didn't plan to talk to you.
只想把你解决掉
She planned to kill you
再把现场布置成自杀的样子
and make it look like suicide.
那杯酒里下了安眠药
That wine was laced with a sleeping pill.
你本应喝下酒  再淹死在润滑油里
You were supposed to drink it and then drown in the oil.
之后  全世界都会认为
And then the world would think that you were
多年来  你因为派克一家的遭遇倍受煎熬
Racked with guilt over the Pikes all these years
最后决定自杀
And that you finally decided to commit suicide
一旦有人发现你的尸体
Once your body was discovered,
大众就会对事情的真相趋之若骛
the public would clamor for the true story..
当然是欣西亚嘴里的真相
Cynthia's true story..
而你则被塑造成一个恶棍
With you now cast as the villain.
我们扭打起来
We struggled.
她失去了平衡  撞到洗脸盆上
She lost her balance and fell against the sink and...
她撞到了头
Hit her head.
我本该找人来救她
I should've called for help,
可我想就此做个了断
But I just wanted it to be over.
所以  我
So I...
把她拖向浴缸
I dragged her to the tub and...
我
I...
把她推倒
I pushed her in.
其实  我已经是死人了
You see, I was already dead.
就想继续当死人
I just wanted to keep it that way.
听说  你们已经抓到人了
I heard you made an arrest.
具体情况可以看早间新闻
You can hear all about it in the morning news.
得了  我在这件案子上全力帮助你们
Oh, come on, after all the help I gave you on this case,
难道你就不能多透露点消息吗
You can't give me any more information than that?
倒不是不能  不过我在想
Well, I could, but I just keep thinking
如果不是你  案子也许就不会发生
That if it wasn't for you, there wouldn't be a case in the first place.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
你采访过的每个与欣西亚过去有关联的人
Tutte le persone del passato di Cynthia that you interviewed..
你用什么方法让他们知道
How did you manage to let every one of them know
你和欣西亚在联系呢
That you were in contact with her?
你在暗示什么
What are you implying?
你想让人发现其中的端倪  然后去报警
You wanted someone to put two and two together  and call the cops.
把欣西亚扔进监狱
You wanted Cynthia in prison.
这样一来  你和欣西亚之间的合约就会无效
That way, you could tear up the contract you had with her
接着  按照自己的想法写书
And write the story you wanted to write
编个能增加销量的结局
With an ending that would sell more books.
可你自己不能向当局告发欣西亚
I mean, you couldn't call the authorities yourself.
那样的话  故事的命运要如何呢
What kind of story would that be?
理论还算可听
That's a lovely theory,
即便如此  欣西亚·德恩也不是我杀的
But even if it's true, I didn't kill Cynthia Dern.
没干过任何违法的事情
I didn't even do anything illegal.
这不关违法的事
Oh, no, no, no, it's not illegal.
只是很恶心
It's just slimy.
所以你这张特别通行证作废了
So your, uh, all-access pass has been revoked.
还有件事
Oh, and one more thing..
有一天  就在不久的将来
One day, and one day not far from now,
我会把这个故事写进自己的小说
I'm gonna use this in a book.
苏珊·梅勒已收监
Susan Mailer's in booking.
这么多年来
Mm. All these years,
她都在纠正以前犯下的过错  一直在做弥补
Trying to do the right thing, trying to make amends...
可因为欣西亚的贪婪  到头来还是要坐牢
Because of Cynthia's greed, she's gonna end up in jail.
想看大团圆结局
If you're looking for a happy ending,
你恐怕走错地方了
You've come to the wrong place.
下次我想去  第二大道的按摩院试试
Next time, I guess I'll just  try that massage parlor on 2nd avenue.
说说而已
Just kidding.
实际上  这种故事哪里会有大团圆结局
Actually, who needs a happy ending when you have a story with
故事的人物制造已死的假象
people pretending to be dead,
隐姓埋名
Living under assumed names,
布下自杀假象  为了报复而杀人
Plotting fake suicides and murder for revenge?
我很高兴看着你这样自娱自乐
You know, I'm glad to see that you're entertained
可我还得给迈克尔·高德曼打电话
I, however, have to call michael Goldman
告诉他  自己的妻子是个反社会份子
And let him know that his wife was a sociopath.
你也要通知贾内德·斯万斯托
But you also get to call Jared Swanstrom and tell him
告诉他  不必对苏珊·梅勒的死负责
That he's no longer responsible for Susan Mailer's death.
事实上苏珊·梅勒还活着
As a matter of fact, Susan Mailer's still alive.
却导致了欣西亚的死
Which is why Cynthia is now dead.
你总是这么破坏气氛吗
Wow, you are all about the cloud, aren't you?
从不懂得  拨云见日
Never the silver ling.
好吧  也许这个会让你开心点
Okay. Maybe this might cheer you up a little bit.
你赢的
Your winnings.
我赢的吗
My winnings?
别故作扭捏  那把牌是你让我的
Oh, don't play coy with me. You threw your hand.
好吧  我只是做个好人
All right, I was trying to be nice.
不想让你在朋友面前下不来台
I didn't want to embarrass you in front of your friends.
现在我们两清了
Now we're even,
再决雌雄怎么样
So what do you say to a little showdown?
面对面  单打独斗
Head-To-Head. Toe-To-Toe.
赢家通吃
Winner take all.
搞定女人[西班牙语]
Mano a mujer.
搞定女人
"Hand to woman"?
无论付出什么
Whatever it takes.
-就这么办  -别手软
- You're on. - No mercy.
-我会害你伤心的  -受伤的那个是你吧
- I'm gonna make you hurt. - Oh, you're gonna get hurt.
-赌什么  -自尊心或衣服
- What are we playing for? - Pride. Or clothing.
我带了一袋小熊橡皮糖
I think I got a bag of gummy bears.
洗牌
Shuffle.
成交
Deal.
会打德州扑克吗
Comfy with texas hold'em?
是扑克都会打
I'm comfy so long as my cards come from the top of the deck.
看看你还有什么本事
Huh. What you got up your sleeves?
要见识一下  结实的臂膀之外的本领吗
Aside from my muscular arms?